ALEX POMA

Data Engineer Specialist

+51 973119856

alex.poma.iis@gmail.com







I'm passionate about data, I'm currently working at Rimac Seguros as Data Engineer Specialist. I consider myself a self-taught person, who loves technology and process automation, I have been fortunate to cooperate with wonderful teamworks, participating in the different phases of the development of pipelines. I have been working with data for several years, also have the ease to work in a team, as well as efficiently solve problems and achieve the productivity goals set by the company and my teamwork.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Data Engineer Specialist

Rimac Seguros | Feb 2022 - Now

I'm part of the Tribu Data, a member of the Support GCP team, responsible for the creation of different Data Pipelines and their deployment using different GCP technologies.

- Development of Airflow's DAGs for data ingest and improvement of monitoring processes.
- Cloud Functions creation for automation process.
- Implementation of the proceso automático, for the automatic execution of DAGs.
- Review of DataFlow processes for Data Entries loading.
- Process scheduling with Cloud Scheduler.
- Creating of tables and scripts in BigQuery.
- Deployment pipelines in Jenkins for deploy in GCP.
- Use of Agile methodologies complemented with Scrum.

GCP | Cloud Function | Composer | Airflow | Cloud Scheduler | BigQuery | DataFlow | Looker Studio | Python | Git | Jenkins

Data Engineer

TCS | Nov 2020 - Feb 2022

Was member of the AWS Support team, responsible for creating and maintaining different data pipelines using Cloud technologies and SCRUM methodologies.

- Part of the RIMAC Seguros project for the implementation of the BigData ecosystems on AWS.
- Create workflows using AWS Step Function.
- Creation of Python Jobs on AWS Glue for data processing automation.
- Triggers generation in AWS Lambda.
- Scheduling works with AWS CloudWatch.
- Creation of tables and scripts in Athena and Redshift.
- Implementation and optimization of scripts in Presto SQL.
- Logs review, correction and optimization of potential errors.
- Creation and optimization of Dashboards using Power BI.
- Use of Agile methodologies complemented with Scrum.

 $AWS \mid Lambda \mid Glue \mid Step \; Function \mid CloudWatch \mid Athena \mid Redshift \mid Python \mid Presto \; SQL \mid PowerBI \mid Power \; Automate \; Auto$

Business Intelligence Analyst

CMAC Tacna | Jun 2018 - Nov 2020

Inside the Caja Tacna I had the opportunity to learn many things about the financial system, also to being part of the Business Intelligence and Analytical Solutions area, where I was able to generate and optimize Scripts in SQLServer, use ETL tools to create OLAP cubes and the generation of Power BI Dashboards.

- Implementation and administration of the Data Warehouse.
- Generation of credit reports using SSRS.
- Generation of data load packages using SSIS.
- Implementation of OLAP Cubes using SSAS, for the generation of managerial reports.
- Automating the SBS Data Extraction Process using SSIS and R.
- Times reduction for the generation of financial periods, with the implementation of an OLAP Cube.
- Implementation of Dashboards using Power Bl.
- Generation and improvement of Scripts in SQL Server.
- Implementation of the Sinergia project that covers the most used and most important reports and management boards for the company's decision making.

SSIS | SSRS | SSAS | PowerBI | MSQL Server | R | DAX | MDX

SKILLS

Technical

Python/SQL/R

AWS/GCP

Spark/Airflow

Big Data

Data Pipelines

Machine Learning

Data Visualization

Professional

Effective communication

Teamwork

Problem solver

Good time management

EDUCATION

Eng. in Computer Science and Systems

Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University

2011 - 2015

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)

Portugués (Professional)

INTERESES

Swimming

Photography

Programming

Cartoons

